Captioning Provided By:
Mtv networks
字幕提供者：
音乐电视网
Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Squidward, my man,
you are perfect.
章鱼哥，我的男人，
你很完美。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
My kelp garden is all wilted.
我的海带花园都枯萎了。
Don't worry, fellows.
别担心，伙计们。
I've got just the thing
to perk you up.
我只有这样的东西
让你振作起来。
"Kelp Grow."
“海带生长。”
Hold still.
保持不动。
They're... pretty...
他们……漂亮……
Patrick?
帕特里克？
And  SpongeBob.
还有海绵宝宝。
What are you two doing here?
你们两个在这里做什么？
Patrick is helping me
to do good deeds today.
帕特里克正在帮助我
今天要做善事。
Like trimming your kelp garden.
就像修剪你的海带花园一样。
Stop eating my kelp!
别再吃我的海带了！
Ok, ok, geez.
好吧，好吧，哎呀。
Try to help a fellow out.
尝试帮助一个人。
I'll just have to eat
this ice cream cone instead.
我只需要吃饭
这个蛋卷冰淇淋代替。
Oh, do you like to
eat ice cream, Patrick?
哦，你喜欢吗
吃冰淇淋吗，帕特里克？
Hmm...
唔...
Yeah.
是的。
Then have some more.
然后再吃一些。
Whoa.
哇哦。
Still want that ice cream?
还想要那个冰淇淋吗？
Why, I do.
为什么，我愿意。
Thanks, Squidward.
谢谢，章鱼哥。
Want some, SpongeBob?
想要一些吗，海绵宝宝？
Last one to the cone
is a rotten clam.
最后一个到达锥体
是一个烂蛤蜊。
Are you done yet?
你完成了吗？
All done.
全部完成。
Wow, I wish I had a bottle of
that "Kelp Grow" stuff.
哇，我希望我有一瓶
“海带生长”的东西。
Here you go, SpongeBob.
给你，海绵宝宝。
Thank you, Patrick.
谢谢你，帕特里克。
You know, my shoes
feel kind of tight.
你知道，我的鞋子
感觉有点紧。
Nice and roomy.
漂亮又宽敞。
Do you want
your grow-juice back?
你想要吗
你的生长汁回来了吗？
Oh, no, I only paid for it.
哦，不，我只是付了钱。
I wouldn't want to
deprive you of it.
我不想
剥夺你的权利。
Ok.
好的。
But you said you didn't want it.
但你说过你不想要它。
Fine, why don't you two use it
for your... good deeds?
好吧，你们两个为什么不使用它呢？
为了你的……善行？
That's a great idea, Squidward.
这是个好主意，章鱼哥。
Yeah, I'll go first.
是的，我先走了。
What did you do?
你做了什么？
Ooh...
哦...
Quite an improvement,
don't you think?
相当大的进步，
你不觉得吗？
Oh, yes, I agree completely.
哦，是的，我完全同意。
Come on, Patrick,
let's do some good deed-ing.
来吧，帕特里克，
让我们做一些善事吧。
Yay.
耶。
Hey, get back here.
嘿，回到这里吧。
And fix my nose.
并修复我的鼻子。
Hey, Gary, that shell of yours
looks a little cramped.
嘿，加里，你的那个外壳
看起来有点局促。
Meow.
喵。
There, now you've got
plenty of space.
在那里，现在你已经有了
有足够的空间。
Meow.
喵。
Ah-ha, they went this way.
啊哈，他们朝这边走了。
Meow-meow, meow-meow-meow.
喵喵，喵喵喵。
Meow-meow, meow.
喵喵，喵。
Oh, tell me about it.
哦，告诉我吧。
Meow.
喵。
There he is.
他就在那里。
Get ready.
准备。
Now, Patrick.
现在，帕特里克。
Huh?
啊？
There you go, Mr. Krabs.
好了，蟹老板。
You always wanted to
make "big" money.
你一直想
赚“大”钱。
Good deed accomplished.
好事已成。
I ask for no reward.
我不求任何回报。
You're a saint,
SpongeBob,  a saint.
你是一位圣人，
海绵宝宝，圣人。
I know.
我知道。
And it is a burden I must carry.
这是我必须背负的重担。
But time's a-wasting,
we need another good deed.
但时间却很浪费
我们需要另一件好事。
Oh, I've got one.
哦，我有一个。
Um, you know that thing?
嗯，你知道那件事吗？
Um, right, that thing
that we did that day.
嗯，对了，那个东西
我们那天所做的。
No, the other one, um.
不，另一个，嗯。
Oh, um...
哦，嗯...
Uh, thing...
呃，事情...
SpongeBob...
海绵宝宝...
Hey!
嘿！
Look at what you did to me.
看看你对我做了什么。
You better fix my nose,
or you'll hear from my lawyer.
你最好把我的鼻子修一下
或者你会收到我律师的来信。
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Yeah, you'll be ugly again.
是的，你又会变得丑陋。
Yes, I'm sure.
是的，我确定。
Hmm, how to fix his nose.
嗯，如何修复他的鼻子。
Well, if you turn
the bottle upside-down
好吧，如果你转身
瓶子倒过来
maybe it will shrink it.
也许它会缩小它。
Patrick, that's brilliant!
帕特里克，太棒了！
No, wait, don't.
不，等等，不要。
Didn't work.
没用。
Well, try it again.
好吧，再试一次。
Hmm, I think I'll just
even him out.
嗯，我想我会
连他也出来了。
First, a bigger head.
首先，头要大。
Now his body is too small.
现在他的身体还太小了。
Right, too small.
对了，太小了。
Arms are too short.
胳膊太短了。
Legs are too short.
腿太短了。
Other arm.
另一只手臂。
Feet too small.
脚太小了。
Teeth.
牙齿。
Belly button.
肚脐。
Mwah, perfect.
哇，完美。
I look horrible.
我看起来很可怕。
Ew...
呃……
Ugh, he  inked.
呃，他画了墨。
Well, pardon my anatomy.
好吧，请原谅我的解剖学。
What's happening?
发生什么事了？
All right.
好的。
What did you do to me?
你对我做了什么？
I know, I know, uh...
我知道，我知道，呃……
Made you a monster.
让你变成了怪物。
And a giant.
还有一个巨人。
A giant monster.
一个巨大的怪物。
I don't want to be
a giant, lumbering monster.
我不想成为
一个巨大而笨重的怪物。
What'll I do now?
我现在该怎么办？
That's easy.
这很容易。
Play giant, lumbering
monster tag.
扮演巨人，笨重
怪物标签。
Yeah, yeah, you chase us.
是啊是啊，你追我们。
And we run around
and scream like crazy.
我们到处跑
并疯狂地尖叫。
Try and catch us,
giant monster Squidward.
尝试抓住我们，
巨型怪物章鱼哥。
SpongeBob, come back here.
海绵宝宝，回来吧。
This is really fun.
这真的很有趣。
I know, we should do this,
, more often.
我知道，我们应该这样做，
，更频繁。
Monster!
怪物！
Crowd: Monster!
众人：怪物！
Monster.
怪物。
Huh?
啊？
You are very good at
pretending, Squidward.
你很擅长
假装，章鱼哥。
Look how you're all
sweaty and angry.
看看你们都怎么样
满头大汗又生气。
And you got the whole town
to play along.
然后你就得到了整个城镇
一起玩。
What the?
什么？
Kick him.
踢他。
Let's skin him
and make back-bacon.
我们来剥他的皮
并制作培根。
Scoop out his eyeballs
and use 'em as...
挖出他的眼珠子
并将它们用作...
giant, misshapen soccer balls.
巨大的、畸形的足球。
Yeah, yeah...
是啊是啊...
Wait, maybe he's a nice monster
等等，也许他是个不错的怪物
like in my storybook.
就像我的故事书里那样。
Oh, right, I hadn't
thought of that.
哦，对了，我没有
想到了这一点。
Well, are you?
嗯，你是吗？
Oh, goodness gracious, yes.
哦，天哪，是的。
Squidward is the nicest
giant of them all.
章鱼哥最帅了
他们都是巨人。
Yeah, Squidward, tell 'em
about all those times
是的，章鱼哥，告诉他们
关于所有那些时间
you didn't
punch me in the face.
你没有
打我的脸。
Even though you
really wanted to.
即使你
真的很想。
Oh, quiet, you moron!
噢，安静点，你这个白痴！
He hurt
the little one's feelings.
他受伤了
小孩子的感受。
Why, that's not
very nice at all.
为什么，那不是
非常好。
Take him down, boys.
把他打倒，孩子们。
Ow!
噢！
This ought to fix him, ha-ha.
这样应该可以解决他的问题了，哈哈。
Ok, ok, I'm nice.
好吧好吧，我很好。
Now will you leave me alone?
现在你能留下我一个人吗？
Oh, yeah? Then prove it.
哦，是吗？然后证明一下。
Yeah, are you
nice enough to... um...
是啊，你是吗
足够好...嗯...
Compliment me on my new hairdo?
夸我的新发型吗？
Uh, sure, whatever.
呃，当然，无论如何。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Let the junior guppies
camp out under your toenails?
让小孔雀鱼
在你的脚趾甲下扎营？
Take me to the top of
Mount Humongous?
带我到山顶
巨大山？
Whee...
呼……
Blow on my old windmill.
吹我的旧风车。
Do my homework?
我做作业吗？
Dust my attic?
给我的阁楼除尘？
Feed my snail?
喂我的蜗牛吗？
Wow, this giant really is
friendly, after all.
哇这个巨人真的是
毕竟，友好。
He taught my grandmother
how to read.
他教我祖母
如何阅读。
He helped me start my own
blimp ride company.
他帮助我开始了自己的事业
飞艇乘坐公司。
He helped me build a...
他帮助我建立了一个...
a... a...
一个...一个...
Gesundheit.
完全正确。
Crowd: Ahem.
众人：咳咳。
What?
什么？
He didn't say bless you.
他没有说祝福你。
Get him!
抓住他！
Where'd he go?
他去哪儿了？
Is that him over there?
那边是他吗？
Uh... I'm a lamppost.
呃...我是一根灯柱。
Oh.
哦。
Well, let's go check
down by the creek.
嗯，我们去检查一下
就在小溪边。
We'll teach him to dip his feet.
我们会教他浸脚。
Well, Squidward, I guess
this is your new life.
嗯，章鱼哥，我想
这是你的新生活。
And this is your new bed.
这是你的新床。
Good night, old life.
晚安，老生活。
I'll miss you.
我会想念你。
SpongeBob: Good night,
Squidward.
海绵宝宝：晚安，
章鱼哥。
Where are you?
你在哪里？
SpongeBob: Patrick and I
are having a sleepover...
海绵宝宝：帕特里克和我
正在过夜...
in your bellybutton.
在你的肚脐里。
What the- get out of there.
怎么了——离开那里。
You two have ruined my life.
你们两个毁了我的生活。
Oh, Patrick, this is terrible.
哦，帕特里克，这太糟糕了。
Squidward did not like
the kindness we did him.
章鱼哥不喜欢
我们对他的善意。
So?
所以？
We shall do him another.
我们再给他做一次。
SpongeBob: We did it.
海绵宝宝：我们做到了。
What the?
什么？
Since our last kindness
didn't go so well
自从我们上次的善意
进展不太顺利
we brought you a new one.
我们给你带来了一件新的。
A giant clarinet?
巨型单簧管？
And it sounds divine.
这听起来很神圣。
Ah...
啊...
Now I'm too small to play
my giant clarinet.
现在我太小了，不能玩
我的巨型单簧管。
It was the most beautiful thing
I've ever played.
这是最美的事情
我曾经玩过。
Well, at least I still
have my kelp garden.
嗯，至少我还是
有我的海带花园。
What?
什么？
You cut it down?
你把它砍掉了吗？
We used your kelp to make
a kelp-mâché clarinet.
我们用你的海带做了
海带混合单簧管
Oh, I thought
I told that kid not to
哦，我以为
我告诉那孩子不要
put the organic sea cucumber on
top of the free-range anemones.
放上有机海参
自由放养海葵的顶部。
Well, at least my flowers
survived the trip.
好吧，至少我的花
这次旅行幸存下来。
SpongeBob, would you please
find your own flowers to sniff?
海绵宝宝，你愿意吗
找到你自己的花来闻？
What about Patrick, does he have
to find his own flowers too?
帕特里克呢，他有吗？
也去寻找属于自己的花吗？
what are you
talking about, nitwit?
你是什么
在谈论，白痴？
He doesn't even have a nose.
他甚至没有鼻子。
Of course I have
a nose, Squidward.
我当然有
一个鼻子，章鱼哥。
Why, it's at plain as
the nose on my...
为什么，很简单
鼻子在我的...
Face?
脸？
Oh-ho...
哦嚯...
You're right, Squidward.
你是对的，章鱼哥。
My floors.
我的地板。
Think fast, Squiddy.
快想一想，乌贼。
I got your nose.
我抓住了你的鼻子。
You do?
你做？
Yeah, I got it...
是的，我明白了...
right here.
就在这里。
Patrick: Give it, give it here.
帕特里克：给它，给这里。
If you want it,
you gotta go get it.
如果你想要的话，
你得去拿它。
There.
那里。
Well, SpongeBob, what do
you think of my new nose?
那么，海绵宝宝，该怎么办
你想到我的新鼻子了吗？
Patrick,
that's not a nose, that's a...
帕特里克，
那不是鼻子，那是……
Hermit crab.
寄居蟹。
I guess I'll always be
a noseless freak.
我想我会永远是
一个没有鼻子的怪物
Hey, it's not so abnormal
to be noseless.
嘿嘿，这也没什么不正常的吧
变得没有鼻子。
Just look around.
看看周围吧。
Lots of fish don't have noses.
很多鱼没有鼻子。
Yeah, but all my friends
have noses.
是的，但是我所有的朋友
有鼻子。
You, Squidward, Sandy,
even Mr. Krabs.
你，章鱼哥，桑迪，
甚至是蟹老板。
There y'are.
你在那里。
Well, Patrick, if you're
so concerned about
not having a nose
好吧，帕特里克，如果你是
如此关心
没有鼻子
why don't you just get a new one
stitched onto your face?
你为什么不买一件新的呢
缝在你脸上吗？
I can do that?
我能做到吗？
Woman: Dr. Gauze, dial 118...
女：Gauze 医生，拨打 118...
Well, what do you think?
嗯，你觉得怎么样？
Sorry, Doc.
对不起，博士。
I don't really think it's me.
我真的不认为这是我。
That's a-ok, that's cool.
没关系，这很酷。
As lead surgeon here, I take
the hypothetical oath
作为这里的首席外科医生，我认为
假设的誓言
which means I will not stop.
这意味着我不会停止。
I will not  rest.
我不会休息。
I will not cut a single toenail
我不会剪一个脚趾甲
until the customer
is 100 percent satisfied.
直到顾客
是百分百满意的。
So please, browse our
extensive wall of noses.
所以请浏览我们的
宽阔的鼻壁。
And I will patiently await
your final decision.
而我会耐心等待
你的最终决定。
Ok, well, let's see, hmm.
好吧，让我们看看，嗯。
Excellent choice.
绝佳的选择。
All right, Patrick,
let's unveil the new schnoz.
好吧，帕特里克，
让我们揭开新的schnoz的面纱。
Wait, stop, careful, SpongeBob.
等等，停下来，小心点，海绵宝宝。
This fragile stitching
requires tender care.
这种脆弱的缝线
需要温柔的照顾。
Allow me to carefully
remove the bandages.
请允许我仔细地
取下绷带。
There it is, Patrick.
就是这样，帕特里克。
Your brand-new sniffer.
您的全新嗅探器。
Lookin' good, buddy.
看起来不错，伙计。
Well, I've gotta go to work now.
好吧，我现在得去上班了。
Have fun with your new nose...
祝你的新鼻子玩得开心......
I will.
我会。
Now how do I use this thing?
现在我该如何使用这个东西呢？
What is that smell?
那是什么气味？
Pastries?
糕点？
I never knew
they smelled so good.
我从来不知道
它们闻起来很香。
Well, I guess I won't be
eating those.
嗯，我想我不会
吃那些。
Let's see Patrick destroy these.
让我们看看帕特里克摧毁这些。
All these years, I knew
I was missing out on something.
这些年我就知道
我错过了一些东西。
But I never thought
smelling could be this good.
但我从未想过
闻起来也可以这么好。
What was that horrible smell?
那股可怕的气味是什么？
Onion rings?
洋葱圈？
Sick, nobody told me
about bad smells.
生病了，没人告诉我
关于难闻的气味。
Oh, what is it now?
哦，现在怎么样了？
I'm gonna have to rethink
this whole smelling thing.
我得重新考虑一下
这整个臭东西。
I made it.
我做到了。
At least here at home
I can't be attacked by
those wretched odors.
至少在家里
我不能被攻击
那些难闻的气味。
Bad smells are all around me.
我周围都是难闻的气味。
I cannot live in
these conditions.
我不能住在
这些条件。
Narrator: 48 hours later...
旁白：48小时后……
Hiya, Patrick, I- whoa...
嗨，帕特里克，我——哇……
Hey-hey, lookin' good.
嘿嘿嘿，看起来不错啊
Huh?
啊？
Oh, the smells!
哦，气味！
They're everywhere.
他们无处不在。
It's unbearable.
实在难以忍受。
What's wrong with the pinhead?
针头有什么问题吗？
Oh, it's another one.
哦，这是另一件。
No...
不...
I can't take it.
我受不了。
Where do you think you're going?
你认为你要去哪里？
To do what should've
been done long ago.
去做应该做的事
很久以前就已经完成了。
Sweet Neptune.
甜蜜的海王星。
Imported cheese.
进口奶酪。
This is inexcusable.
这是不可原谅的。
Yuck.
恶心。
What are you doing
with my cheese?
你在做什么
和我的奶酪一起？
Patrick: It's rotten
garbage now.
帕特里克：已经烂了
现在垃圾了。
That's better.
这样更好。
That was my cheese.
那是我的奶酪。
It's supposed to smell
like that, Kelp-for-Brains.
应该有味道
就像这样，海带换大脑。
You are sick, Squidward.
你有病吧，章鱼哥。
That smell again.
又是那个味道。
SpongeBob: One... Two...
海绵宝宝：一……二……
Three...   four....
三……四……
Come on, SquarePants,
be a man!
来吧，方裤，
做个男人吧！
Patrick: You?
帕特里克：你？
Patrick, help.
帕特里克，帮忙。
Oh, I'll help you, all right.
哦，我会帮你的，好吧。
Help stop you from
polluting our world
帮助阻止你
污染我们的世界
with your sweaty holes.
和你出汗的洞。
There.
那里。
I can't work at the Krusty Krab
looking like this.
我不能在蟹堡王工作
看起来像这样。
I'm out of uniform.
我没穿制服了
Well, you can't go to
work smelling like that.
嗯，你不能去
工作就有那样的味道。
Should be thanking me,
SpongeBob.
应该感谢我，
海绵宝宝。
Smells like...
闻起来像...
something greasy.
油腻的东西。
Patrick: Nobody moves!
帕特里克：没人动！
I am ridding this place of
its disgusting stench
我正在摆脱这个地方
其令人厌恶的恶臭
with these scented candles.
用这些香薰蜡烛。
My mouth can't take
these conflicting flavors, augh.
我的嘴无法接受
这些相互冲突的味道，呵呵。
This air freshener
should finish the job.
这款空气清新剂
应该完成工作。
What the barnacles
do you think you're doing?
什么是藤壶
你认为你在做什么？
You're chasing away
all me customers.
你正在追赶
都是我的顾客。
Well, good.
嗯，很好。
No one should have to
eat in this  stench.
没有人应该必须
在这恶臭中吃饭。
What?
什么？
Why, I gotta good mind to...
为什么，我得好好想想……
Say no more, you can
thank me later.
不用多说了，可以
稍后谢谢我。
Right now I've got many more
stink-holes to swab clean.
现在我还有很多
臭洞要擦拭干净。
Oh...
哦...
That new honker of his has
turned him into a complete jerk.
他的新喇叭已经
让他变成了一个彻头彻尾的混蛋。
Hiya, Pat.
你好，帕特。
Take a bath, flea-bag.
洗澡，跳蚤袋。
Mr. Krabs: I've asked y'all here
because we all face
a similar problem.
蟹老板：我已经问过你们了
因为我们都面临着
类似的问题。
The problem being
问题是
a sea-star with a nose
that's gotten way out of hand.
有鼻子的海星
这已经失控了。
Yeah.
是的。
Now what I want to know is
现在我想知道的是
are we gonna
do something about it?
我们要吗
对此做点什么？
Yeah, sure are.
是的，当然是。
Let's give him what for.
让我们给他什么。
Let's hogtie him and run him
out of town on a rail.
我们把他绑起来然后跑吧
乘火车出城。
Sandy and Squidward: Yeah...
桑迪和章鱼哥：是啊……
Come on, SpongeBob,
be a man!
来吧，海绵宝宝，
做个男人吧！
Mr. Krabs?
蟹老板？
Not now, boy.
不是现在，孩子。
We're in the middle of
a public lashing.
我们正处于中间
公开鞭打。
That no-good, nose-flaunting...
那个不好看，鼻子张扬的...
It is not Patrick's fault.
这不是帕特里克的错。
Huh?
啊？
It's the new nose
that has betrayed us.
这是新鼻子
那背叛了我们。
My Grandma SquarePants
always says
我的奶奶方裤
总是说
"punish the nose, not the man."
“惩罚的是鼻子，而不是人。”
Now we're going to need
something foul,
something beyond foul.
现在我们需要
一些肮脏的东西，
超出犯规范围的东西。
A stench that will
blow the socks off
his fungus-infested socks.
一股恶臭将
吹掉袜子
他的长满真菌的袜子
Ok, this should be
stinky enough.
好的，这应该是
够臭的。
I gathered every
sweaty sock, moldy pizza
我收集了每一个
出汗的袜子，发霉的披萨
and rotten piece of fruit
in Bikini Bottom.
和一块腐烂的水果
在比基尼底部。
With a little raw sewage
for good measure.
用少量原污水
为了更好的衡量。
Attaboy.
阿塔博伊。
Now for the moment of truth.
现在到了关键时刻。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
Hello.
你好。
Oh!
哦！
All I wanted was to be able to
smell like the rest of you.
我想要的只是能够
闻起来像你们其他人。
SpongeBob: "Here lies
the nose of Patrick Star, rip."
海绵宝宝：“这里躺着
帕特里克·斯塔的鼻子，撕裂。”
Well, this is terrible.
嗯，这太可怕了。
All Patrick wanted was
to be like the rest of us.
帕特里克想要的只是
像我们其他人一样。
And we punished him for it.
我们因此惩罚了他。
Who cares?
谁在乎？
At least now that pink moron
will leave us alone.
至少现在那个粉红白痴
会让我们独自一人。
Patrick: I heard that.
帕特里克：我听说了。